"Shoddy Construction at the Airport Village."
"Pembangunan Buruk di Desa Bandara!"
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
Garis telapak tangan yang tersembunyi adalah sekeringnya.
The deduction catches fire on the line to the heart.
Garis hati menyalakan api deduksi.
An unexpected trick transcending time and space that confuses Haibara.
Kiat mengejutkan yang melampaui ruang dan waktu membingungkan Haibara.
He sees through the one and only truth.
Dia melihat satu-satunya kebenaran.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
Memiliki penampilan seorang anak kecil dengan kepintaran orang dewasa.
His name is Detective Conan!
Namanya adalah Detektif Conan!
"Ai Haibara is Held in Captivity."
"Kasus Penyekapan Ai Haibara."
Haibara was nowhere to be found.
Haibara tidak ada di mana pun.
If she went shopping she would've been through long time ago.
Dia pasti sudah selesai berbelanja sekarang.
I wonder what happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
If something happened,
Kalau sesuatu terjadi padanya,
it had to have happened on her way back.
pasti terjadi di sini dalam perjalanan pulang.
-Maybe she was run over? -No way!
-Apa dia tertabrak mobil? -Tidak mungkin!
I can't imagine that happened to Haibara.
Aku tidak bisa membayangkan itu terjadi pada Haibara.
A railway crossing accident?
Mungkin dia mengalami kecelakaan di perlintasan kereta.
No way!
Tidak mungkin!
-A muffler? -It's so small!
-Syal? -Kecil sekali!
It has nothing to do with Haibara, does it?
Itu tidak ada hubungannya dengan Haibara.
No.
Ada...
It belongs to the kitten that liked Haibara a lot.
Ini milik anak kucing yang menyukai Haibara.
How cute.
Lucunya!
"Naoshi, Mitsuru Higaki."
"Naoshi, Mitsuru Higaki."
Midoridai. Midoridai. There are places where the space between...
Midoridai, inilah Pos Midoridai. Mungkin ada celah di antara...
What are you looking at kitty?
Apa yang kaulihat, anak kucing?
-It's a terrarium. -Is there something there?
-Itu terarium. -Apa ada sesuatu di dalamnya?
It come out.
Ia keluar.
Oh! It's an Indian Star Turtle.
Itu kura-kura bintang India.
What a beautiful pattern.
Polanya indah.
Wasn't there an import restriction on it?
Bukankah mengimpornya sangat dibatasi?
No need to worry.
Jangan khawatir.
"Mitsuru Higaki (38)" -I bought it at a legitimate shop.
"Mitsuru Higaki (38)" -Aku membelinya di toko yang sah.
What a surprise.
Aku heran.
Chiro seems to like you a lot.
Chiro sangat menyukaimu.
Hey, kitty!
Hei, anak kucing!
-Chiro, where are you? -In here!
-Chiro, kau di mana? -Di sini!
-It fell. -I'm glad we found her.
-Dia jatuh. -Untung kita menemukannya.
No one seems to be home.
Tidak ada orang di rumah.
We went out of our way to bring the cat back, and yet...
Tapi kita datang jauh-jauh ke sini untuk mengembalikan anak kucingnya.
It seems Haibara's not here either.
Haibara juga tidak ada di sini.
The curtains are closed too.
Tirainya juga tertutup.
What's up?
Ada apa?
I wonder if it's hungry...
Mungkin dia lapar...
So, all we got is one kitten?
Yang kalian punya hanya seekor anak kucing.
I wonder where Haibara went?
Ke mana perginya Haibara?
Maybe she was kidnapped?
Mungkin dia diculik.
"I got the girl, so bring the cash!" Like so.
"Aku menahan gadis itu. Bawakan uangnya!"
If so... Maybe the culprit thought this house was loaded?
Apa seseorang mengira di dalam rumah ada uang?
Okay, I got it. Thanks, Officer Chiba.
Baik, aku mengerti. Terima kasih, Detektif Chiba.
There haven't been any reports in this area from this morning.
Tidak ada kecelakaan yang dilaporkan di daerah ini sejak tadi pagi.
I'm sure she'll try to contact us if anything came up.
Dia pasti memberi tahu kita kalau sesuatu telah terjadi.
Haibara, everybody's worried!
Haibara, semua orang mengkhawatirkanmu.
Contact us!
Hubungi kami.
I wonder what happened to me.
Apa yang terjadi padaku?
Where am I?
Di mana aku?
It's already this late?
Apa? Ini sudah siang.
I've been asleep for 5 hours.
Aku tidak percaya aku tertidur selama lima jam.
Indian Star Turtle.
Kura-kura bintang India?
It's Ms. Higaki's house.
Ini rumah Higaki.
That's right, I...
Betul sekali! Aku...
Chiro?
Chiro?
Your muffler got stuck,
Syalmu terlilit.
I'll remove it for you right away.
Aku akan segera membebaskanmu.
See. Stay still.
Diam dulu...
Ma'am?
Bu?
Midoridai, Midoridai.
Midoridai, Midoridai.
This train will remain for five minutes to wait for the express train.
Kereta ini akan berhenti selama lima menit untuk menunggu kereta ekspres.
"Murder in the Shin-Chitose Airport General Purpose Restroom?"
"Pembunuhan di WC Umum Bandara Chitose Baru?"
"Naoshi Higaki (42)"
"Naoshi Higaki (42)"
Higaki? Don't tell me that...
Higaki? Mungkinkah?
I've got to calm down.
Tenang.
I've got to pull free somehow!
Aku harus kabur.
Thank you for the meal.
Terima kasih atas makanannya.
I'm full. I'm really full.
Aku kenyang.
Why don't we try going over to the Higaki residence once more with her?
Kenapa kita tidak membawa anak kucing itu ke tempat Higaki lagi?
Nobody was there, you know.
Tapi dia tidak ada di rumah.
Maybe they came home already, right?
Dia mungkin sudah pulang sekarang.
True, it's better than just staying here.
Duduk di sini tidak ada gunanya.
-Let's go! -Yes.
-Sebaiknya kita pergi. -Ya.
It came off!
Aku bisa membukanya!
Help!
Tolong!
The culprit's still here!
Pelakunya masih di sini!
Nobody's home after all?
Di rumah tidak ada orang?
What?
Apa?
Yeah. I rang the bell six times but no answer.
Ya, aku menekan bel pintu enam kali, tapi dia tidak menjawab.
Give me a break. Mrs. Higaki told me to come at this time and yet...
Aku tidak tahu harus berbuat apa. Dia memintaku datang sekarang.
I've got no choice.
Aku tidak punya pilihan.
Can you tell her that I'll be back later, Chiro.
Beri tahu dia bahwa aku akan kembali lain kali, Chiro.
See you.
Dah.
He tells the cat to relay the message and left.
Dia meninggalkan pesan pada kucing dan pergi.
It's Officer Chiba!
Detektif Chiba.
Oh, just a while ago
Benda aneh baru dikirim ke pos polisi di Jalan Bandara.
The Youth Detective Squad badge?
Apa? Lencana Kelompok Detektif Cilik?
Right, a truck driver who was fixing a flat tyre in the area picked it up
Ya. Pengemudi yang mengganti ban kempis di daerah itu menyerahkannya.
Everybody's worried!
Semua orang mengkhawatirkanmu.
Contact us!
Hubungi kami.
"The Youth Detective Squad."
"Kelompok Detektif Cilik."
It's pretty far. We've been driving for about an hour already.
Jauh juga. Kita sudah bermobil selama satu jam.
Accurately, it's been 50 minutes!
Sebenarnya, baru 50 menit.
It's the police box near the intersection of Airport Blvd.
Rupanya, itu pos polisi di dekat persimpangan.
We'll get there in about two or three minutes.
Kita akan sampai beberapa menit lagi.
You mean she came this far? Haibara?
Apa Haibara benar-benar pergi sejauh ini?
It's quite unthinkable.
Sulit dibayangkan.
It's near the airport and yet a new residential district's been built.
Sejumlah rumah baru telah dibangun di dekat bandara.
Seems like the selling point are convenience and complete sound proof.
Rupanya nilai jualnya adalah kenyamanan dan peredaman suara total.
There's the police box!
Aku melihat pos polisi!
"The Airport Village."
"Desa Bandara."
What a big sign.
Papan reklame besar!
Practically all of them seems to have been sold.
Ternyata sebagian besar sudah terjual.
This is it.
Ini dia.
No doubt about, it's Ai's!
Itu jelas lencana Ai.
I'm sure that she was kidnapped and threw this out along the way!
Haibara mungkin melemparnya ke tanah
To let us know where she is!
untuk mengatakan dia dibawa ke mana.
But we haven't even been contacted by the culprit yet,
Tapi kita belum mendengar kabar dari penculik.
so it's too early to conclude that this is a kidnapping case.
Kita tidak bisa berasumsi dia telah diculik.
This is the key for the handcuffs?
Ini kunci borgol.
Ma'am. Is the culprit here?
Bu, apa pelakunya ada di sini?
Is this the key for the handcuffs?
Apa ini kunci borgol?
Ma'am, can you bend down?
Bisa kau berlutut?
Stay still okay?
Jangan bergerak.
Thank you, Ai. I'll untie you right away.
Terima kasih, Ai. Aku akan segera melepaskanmu.
Police. Is anybody home?
Saya dari kepolisian. Apa di situ ada orang?
This is the Mitsuru Higaki residence, isn't it?
Apa ini rumah Mitsuru Higaki?
What's wrong?
Apa yang terjadi?
The fact is I'm here to check on things here on request of the HPD.
Kepolisian Hokkaido meminta saya untuk memeriksa anda.
It's been quite a misfortune, hasn't it?
Itu pasti bencana besar.
No, never mind me, but my husband, Naoshi...
Saya baik-baik saja. Sudahkah anda menangkap Naoshi...
Has the culprit who killed my husband been arrested?
Orang yang membunuh suami saya?
No, unfortunately.
Sayangnya belum.
An investigator is heading over here from Hokkaido regarding this.
Penyelidik dari Hokkaido akan datang untuk bertanya tentang itu.
I don't know anything.
Saya tidak tahu apa-apa.
I was tied up right through in this house, you see.
Saya diikat di rumah saya ini selama itu.
Well, all I want to ask you is about Mr. Higaki's acquaintances.
Saya berharap untuk menanyakan hubungan suami anda.
Yes, if it's about that.
Saya bisa memberi tahu anda tentang itu.
Talk about unlucky.
Itu nasib buruk.
Are you feeling better?
Kau lebih lega?
Yes, but I'm sorry to have worried all of you.
Ya. Maaf sudah membuat semua orang khawatir.
No, it's great that you're safe.
Tidak. Aku senang kau baik-baik saja.
Some shopping experience it was.
Perjalanan belanja luar biasa.
Is this a coincidence?
Kebetulan, ya?
The lady really went through a terrible coincidence.
Itu kebetulan yang mengerikan baginya.
To think that her husband was killed while the house was being robbed.
Seseorang membunuh suaminya saat rumahnya dirampok.
Yes. I found out about the case on TV.
Ya. Saya mendengar tentang kejadian itu di berita.
But, I couldn't move at all.
Tapi saya tidak bisa bergerak.
Just like Ai over there.
Saya dengan Ai.
-Haibara. -What?
-Haibara. -Apa?
You said a terrible coincidence, right?
Kau menganggapnya kebetulan yang mengerikan, kan?
Do you really think so? You think that all that's a coincidence?
Itukah yang kaupikirkan? Kau benar-benar berpikir semuanya hanya kebetulan?
What?
Apa?
Why did the robber do what the robber did to you back then?
Kenapa perampok itu menyeretmu ke dalam rumah?
If left as it is, people would've thought the resident wasn't home.
Kalau dia membiarkanmu saja, kau akan mengira di rumah tidak ada orang.
Besides, why were you put to sleep twice?
Lalu, kenapa kau dibius dua kali?
Did the robber stay that long in this house?
Apa si perampok benar-benar di rumah ini selama itu?
The robber was having trouble opening the safe.
Butuh waktu untuk membuka brankas.
-She's the one who said that, right? -Right.
-Itu yang dia katakan, kan? -Ya.
When you were put to sleep the second time, what was she doing?
Saat kau dibius kedua kalinya, apa yang dia lakukan?
What?
Apa?
I'm asking if you saw the robber and that lady at the same time.
Aku bertanya, apa kau pernah melihat perampok dan dia pada saat bersamaan.
Help!
Tolong!
The culprit's still here!
Pelakunya masih di sini!
I couldn't have.
Aku tidak bisa.
I was covered with a towel from right behind me
Dia muncul dari belakang dan menutup wajahku,
and my vision was blocked right away.
jadi aku tak melihat apa-apa.
More so, I didn't have the composure to be worried about anybody else.
Aku tidak dalam posisi untuk khawatir tentang..
Not even a tinge! Don't tell me you think that lady is...
Tunggu! Jangan katakan kau...
You suspect that she's playing both of the role, don't you, Edogawa?
Kaupikir wanita itu dan si perampok adalah orang yang sama.
-What? -That's ridiculous.
-Apa? -Itu konyol!
But why would she do something like that?
Tapi kenapa dia melakukannya?
Maybe she used me to establish her alibi for murder.
Dia memanfaatkan aku untuk menciptakan alibi buat pembunuhan itu.
Robber and murder.
Perampokan dan pembunuhan.
Haibara got messed up in it.
Juga Haibara, yang diseret ke dalam rumah.
Maybe it was no coincidence, but actually a put-up-job.
Mungkin bukan kebetulan, tapi semuanya adalah bagian dari rencana.
Are you saying Chiro was used to set me up as a witness for her alibi?
Maksudmu, dia memakai Chiro agar aku menguatkan alibinya?
If she made a round trip to Hokkaido
Takkan ada yang mencurigainya
after putting you to sleep, she wouldn't be suspected.
kalau dia ke dan dari Hokkaido saat kau tidur.
-What if she set up a plan like that? -It can't be.
-Bagaimana kalau itu rencananya? -Itu mustahil.
Because she couldn't have committed the crime.
Mustahil dia bisa melakukan kejahatan.
It's only an hour and a half if you take a direct flight to Shin-Chitose.
Penerbangan ke Bandara Chitose Baru tinggal waktu satu setengah jam.
From here to the airport. Just how long does it take?
Berapa lama waktu yang dibutuhkan untuk pergi dari sini ke bandara?
If you take a car from here, it's an hour,
Sekitar satu jam dengan mobil, berarti total dua setengah jam.
If it's two hours and a half one way, then a round trip would take...
Kalau dua setengah jam sekali jalan, perjalanan pulang pergi menjadi...
Five hours!
Lima jam!
The time she had to wait for the victim to come to the airport
Menunggu korban di bandara akan memakan waktu juga.
It would take at least five hours and a half.
Setidaknya butuh lima setengah jam.
No, but...
Tidak, tapi...
After I woke up, I saw the lady a little after 14:00.
Aku bangun dan melihatnya pukul 14:00 lebih sedikit.
I was only asleep at most only for five hours.
Aku tertidur selama hampir lima jam.
It also bothers me that your badge was found on Airport Blvd.
Aku juga ingin tahu kenapa lencana detektifmu ditemukan di Jalan Bandara.
That's right, the door chime!
Itu dia! Bel pintu!
Somebody came to the door and rang the door chime.
Seseorang datang ke pintu dan menekan bel pintu.
It was about 14:30!
Sekitar pukul 14:30.
It came off!
Aku bisa membukanya!
It's back then!
Pasti itu!
Right, the liquor delivery!
Ya, kiriman toko minuman!
Nobody's home after all?
Di rumah tidak ada orang?
What?
Apa?
Yeah. I rang the bell six times but no answer.
Ya, aku menekan bel pintu enam kali, tapi dia tidak menjawab.
Wait! Six times? I heard only two times.
Tunggu! Enam kali? Aku hanya mendengarnya berdering dua kali.
And not successively but slowly!
Ia tidak berdering terus-menerus. Deringnya lebih lambat.
What?
Apa?
Just as I thought!
Sudah kuduga.
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
The door chime and station announcement were all recording
Bel pintu dan pengumuman pos adalah rekaman yang diputar si pelaku.
If so, everything falls into place!
Semuanya masuk akal.
I sort of get the idea of what you're thinking now, Edogawa.
Kurasa aku mengerti apa yang kaupikirkan, Edogawa.
You think that there were two Higaki residences, right?
Ada dua rumah, kan?
What?
Apa?
What're you talking about?
Apa maksudmu?
I see.
Begitu.
There's not enough time because we're thinking a round trip
Waktu tidak cukup bagi si pelaku untuk ke dan dari Hokkaido.
But, if the place where Haibara woke up
Tapi kalau Haibara terbangun
was at another house near the airport then...
di rumah yang berbeda di dekat bandara...
You mean the place that was on the sign!
Yang diiklankan di papan reklame!
The Airport Village near the airport?
Desa Bandara di dekat bandara?
If Ai was held captive in one of those houses, then...
Ya. Kalau Ai disekap di salah satu rumah itu...
The time to go to the airport won't have be considered!
Si pelaku tidak membutuhkan banyak waktu untuk ke dan dari bandara.
It's two hours saved!
Itu akan menghemat dua jam.
The explanation to the trick of giving the impression that
Kura-kura membuatmu mengira kedua rumah itu satu rumah.
Because you can take the terrarium along!
Seluruh terarium bisa diangkut.
At the same time that the liquor delivery man was asked to come,
Dia memutar rekaman bel pintu di rumah palsu
the recorded chime is rung at the fake house!
saat kiriman toko minuman seharusnya tiba.
I was put to sleep two times so that she could move me and the turtle.
Aku dibius dua kali agar pelaku bisa memindahkan aku dan kura-kura itu.
But, how can you prove that there were two houses?
Tapi bagaimana kita bisa membuktikan ada dua rumah?
This is a big place.
Ada banyak sekali rumah.
The goal is right before our eyes! Can you remember anything else?
Garis finis sudah terlihat. Bisa kau mengingat yang lain?
Well...
Baik...
Chiro.
Chiro!
I'm glad I drank it all!
Untung aku sudah menghabiskannya.
I wonder what that was.
Apa itu tadi?
The can that rolled turned to a different direction?
Kaleng mulai bergulir ke arah yang berbeda?
"Shoddy Construction at the Airport Village."
"Pembangunan Buruk di Desa Bandara!"
Yes. When I woke up again, that can didn't move at all.
Ya. Saat aku bangun kedua kalinya, kaleng bergeming.
I got it! That's got to be it!
Aku tahu! Pasti itu!
Genta, lift up the edge of the table a bit, will you.
Genta, angkat sedikit tepi meja.
Okay.
Baik.
-Like this? -Good. Watch.
-Bagaimana kalau begini? -Baik. Lihat ini.
See, it turned to another direction, right?
Berubah arah, kan?
What does this have to do with Haibara's story?
Apa hubungannya dengan cerita Haibara?
This is what Edogawa's getting at!
Inilah yang ingin dikatakan Edogawa!
"Plastic Bottles Roll Continuously Across the Floor."
"Botol Plastik Terus Bergulir di Lantai."
The floor is like a slide.
Ternyata lantainya seperti seluncuran.
We found out right away from the property developers list.
Saya langsung menemukannya di daftar perusahaan real estat.
I'll send you the picture of this house.
Saya mengirimkan foto rumahnya.
It's true that you're unlucky.
Anda jelas tidak beruntung.
To think that the house that you bought and renovated
Rumah palsu yang anda beli dan renovasi,
was made under shoddy construction.
dibangun dengan buruk.
Was Officer Takagi at the Airport Village?
Apa Detektif Takagi di Desa Bandara?
Shoddy construction is a crime, you see.
Ya. Pembangunan yang buruk adalah kejahatan.
Officer Takagi just happened to be there.
Takagi kebetulan sedang di sana.
Super good job, Youth Detective Squad!
Bagus, Kelompok Detektif Cilik.
Aye!
Ya!
Her motive was really something plain and common,
Dia melakukannya karena alasan biasa dalam kerumitan perceraian.
Is that so?
Begitu.
Which means that she had her eyes on Ai to begin with?
Apa si pelaku mengincar Ai?
Yes. It seems so.
Ya, sepertinya begitu.
Because Ai's intelligent and strong-willed.
Dia cerdas, berkemauan keras, dan sering terlihat memarahimu.
and figured Ai may serve as a great witness.
Dia pikir Ai akan menjadi saksi sempurna.
I wonder if she used to scold me that much?
Apa dia memarahiku sesering itu?
Well, will you please tell the members of the Youth Detective Squad
Bagaimanapun, beri tahu Kelompok Detektif Cilik,
that the case was closed?
kasus telah diselesaikan tanpa masalah.
-Okay. -Bye, then.
-Baik. -Dah.
Hey, Haibara.
Hei, Haibara.
What's up? Smiling like that?
Apa sesuatu terjadi? Kau tersenyum.
Well...
Mungkin.
-What? Tell me, tell me! -Well...
-Apa yang terjadi? Beri tahu kami. -Ya...
What? Really?
Apa? Masa?
I'm glad!
Keren!
-Shall we go then! -Yes!
-Mau pergi? -Ya!
Yes!
Ya!
That Haibara is cheerfully laughing and running...
Haibara kabur dengan senyum di wajahnya...
Hey!
Hei!
-Wait! Tell me too! -It's a secret.
-Tunggu! Ceritakan juga padaku! -Ini rahasia!
Hey, wait!
Hei, tunggu!
Seems like they found a foster home for Chiro and the turtle.
Mereka menemukan seseorang yang mengadopsi Chiro dan kura-kura, ya?
The owner maybe a culprit, but the pets aren't to blame for it.
Meskipun si pemilik melakukan kejahatan, hewan itu tidak bersalah.
"Next Episode."
"Episode Selanjutnya."
Stay away! Stay back.
Mundur. Sebaiknya kau mundur.
Cool it!
Tenang!
-Ayumi! -Ayumi!
-Ayumi! -Ayumi!
Darn!
Sial!
This is a trace of sudden acceleration...
Bekas selip ban?
This is...
Ini...
Just as I thought!
Sudah kuduga.
Next Conan, "A Troublesome Emergency Patient".
Selanjutnya dalam Conan, "Pasien Darurat yang Menyusahkan!"
Next Conan's Hint:
Petunjuk Conan Selanjutnya:
"Clipping."
"Kliping."
Thanks for everything.
Terima kasih atas bantuannya.
I'd help you any day, anytime, Haibara.
Aku akan menyelamatkanmu sesering mungkin, Haibara!
Thank you...
Terima kasih...